Guide to the Brooklyn Bureau of Community Service records ARC.129
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 3: Sheltering Arms Nursery records, 1871-1917; 3517; 2.7 Linear Feet in five boxes
  - Annual Reports, 1872-1891; 66737 (Box 33)
  - "Arte Loane and Fancie Bazaar" program, 1883; 66738 (Box 33)
    Held at the Brooklyn Academy of Music.
- Series 4: Photographs, 1920s-1986; V1991.110; 3521; 4 Linear Feet in eight boxes and one binder
  This collection contains photographic prints, albums, lantern slides, and 35 mm slides, dating from the 1920s to 1986. The photographs were produced for the Brooklyn Bureau of Community Service and its two predecessor organizations, the Brooklyn Bureau of Charities and the Brooklyn Children's Aid Society.
  The photographic prints date from the 1920s to 1986 and are primarily promotional in nature, documenting the services provided by the Bureau. Many of the images feature blind adults and children at work and play. Other subjects include members of the Board of Directors and staff, special events, and Brooklyn street scenes. Many of the photographs were taken by Bernard Ravitz, Paul Parker, Publicity Photographs, and Verna Photographs.
  The lantern slides document life in Brooklyn in the 1920s and 1930s. They include images of tenements (interiors and exteriors), but also the construction of new buildings and what appear to be more affluent sections of the borough. Many of the slides were produced by the Devereaux View Company and James Huntington.
  The 35 mm slides are also primarily promotional in nature, and date from the 1950s to the 1970s.
  Twp additional photographic albums and scrapbooks can be found in Sub-series 1.5: Committee on the Blind and related events and Series 2: Brooklyn Children's Aid Society records.
  - Prints, 66731 (Box Prints by Accession (3 boxes))
  - Oversize prints, 66719 (Box Prints by Accession OS13)
  - Lantern slides, 66732 (Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39)
  - Slides, 66745 (Item Binder V1991.11.290)